A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Humanities and the Arts, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of Wilson McNeil Lowry FA582
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Programs, 1952-1971; IV
  - International Development -- Soviet and East European Fellowship Program -- Memoranda, Reports, 1968 March 19-June 21 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - International Training and Research (ITR) -- South Africa Leader Exchange Program, 1960 September 12-1965 June 17 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - ITR -- Material Sent to International Legal Studies Program Consultants, 1961-1966 January 19 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - ITR -- International Legal Studies (1 of 2), 1962-1963 May 31 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - ITR -- International Legal Studies (2 of 2), 1963 May 31-1964 December 29 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - ITR -- English as a Second Language (1 of 3), 1963 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - ITR -- English as a Second Language (2 of 3), 1964 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - ITR -- English as a Second Language (3 of 3), 1965 March 24-1966 September 1 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - ITR -- General, 1962 August 16-1966 July 26 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - ITR -- Undergraduate Education, 1962 February 28-December 23 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - ITR -- "Non-Western Studies and Undergraduate Education" by George M Beckmann, 1962 October (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - ITR -- Report on Non-Western Studies at Earlham and Antioch Colleges and Additional Note, 1962 December-1963 January (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - ITR -- Report on Non-Western Studies at Earlham and Antioch Colleges, 1962 December 8 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - ITR -- "Non-Western Studies: The Connecticut Valley Group", 1962 December 12 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - ITR -- Language and Linguistics -- General, 1963 December 5-12 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - ITR -- "Non-Western Studies: The Limits of Faculty Re-Training and Some Suggestions", 1963 December 14 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - ITR -- Grant Request Items, 1964 February 11-1966 May 17 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - ITR -- "Review of The Ford Foundation's International Legal Studies Program", 1964 March (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - ITR -- Language and Linguistics -- "A Survey of Intensive Programs in the Uncommon Languages" by Roy Andrew Miller, 1964 August-September (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - ITR -- Language and Linguistics -- Indiana Second Annual Report, 1964 August (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - ITR -- Center for Applied Linguistics, 1964 November 16-1965 August 10 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - ITR -- American Universities Field Studies, 1965 January 25-1965 August 9 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - ITR -- Language and Linguistics Grant Requests, 1965 June 3 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - ITR -- South Africa -- Memoranda -- Foundation Policies and Work, 1965 July 22-August 5 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - ITR -- Proposed International Legal Studies Agency, 1965 November-1966 May 10 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Overseas Development (OD) -- "Report of Meeting on University Projects Under Ford Foundation Grants in South and South East Asia", 1959 December 7 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - OD -- South and Southeast Asia -- Evaluations and Miscellaneous Reports, 1959 December 7-1963 April 8 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - OD -- "Review of Ford Foundation Program in Israel and Turkey" by Benson E. Ginsburg, 1961 May 31 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - OD -- South and Southeast Asia -- Harvard-Pakistan Planning Commission Project, 1962 March-August (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - OD -- General, 1962 June 14-1966 August 12 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - OD -- Administration, 1962 July 16-1965 August 31 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - OD -- Ad Hoc Trustee Committee on OD Program -- Meeting Materials, 1962 August 23-1963 March 29 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - OD -- Ad Hoc Trustee Committee on Personnel for Overseas Assignments, 1962 August 23-1963 March 5 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - OD -- Personnel for Overseas/International Development Reports, 1962 September 6-December 4 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - OD -- Overseas Development, South and Southeast Asia, Review of 1962 and Projection of 1963, 1962 December 11 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - OD -- "Personnel for Overseas Development", 1962 December 15 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - OD -- "Notes on Bethuel M. Webster's Trip to New Delhi, Calcutta, Karachi, Beirut", 1963 January 21-February 5 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - OD -- Latin America and Caribbean -- General, 1963 February 27-1966 October 10 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - OD -- "Report of the Trustees Ad Hoc Committee on the Overseas Development Program", 1963 March (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - OD -- "Meeting of Representatives, South and Southeast Asia Program, New Delhi, February 15-16, 1963", 1963 March 22 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - OD -- "Evaluation of Experience in Overseas Programs, South and Southeast Asia", 1963 May 17-September 17 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - OD -- Middle East and Africa -- General, 1963-1966 August 9 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - OD -- South and Southeast Asia -- General, 1963 November 11-1966 October 19 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - OD -- South and Southeast Asia Program Fiscal Year Reports, 1963 December 9-1965 December 30 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - OD -- Grant Lists, 1964 October 30-1965 September 21 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - OD -- Aid Technical Assistance Questionnaire, 1964 November-1965 February 3 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - OD -- "Reflections on the Foundation's Experience in Overseas Development" by F. C. Ward, 1964 November 29 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - OD -- "The Political Situation in the Dominican Republic" by Robert A. Mayer, 1965 September 10 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - OD -- South and Southeast Asia -- New Delhi Office Building, 1966 January 13-18 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - OD -- Agriculture Reports and Outline by F. F. Hill and Related Memoranda, 1966 February 8-April 27 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - OD -- Reviews of Overseas Development Program, 1966 March 14-August 8 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Public Affairs (PA) -- University of Wisconsin, Madison Report, 1960 January 13-1964 February 11 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - PA -- Southeastern Michigan Metropolitan Community Research Corporation and PENJERDEL, 1961 October 20-1964 January 10 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - PA -- Youth Studies Center -- Reports of Visits, 1961 November 20 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - PA -- General Correspondence and Memoranda, 1962 January 16-1966 August 23 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - PA -- University of Wisconsin, Milwaukee Report Re: University Projects and Proposals, 1962 January 23-1964 January 24 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - PA -- Urban Transportation -- Rand Corporation -- Reports, Memoranda, 1962 July 31-1963 May (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - PA -- MIT and Harvard Joint Center for Urban Studies, 1962 October 3-1965 September 1 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - PA -- Urban Extension Program at University of Illinois, 1962 November-1964 January 3 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - PA -- University of Wisconsin Fox Valley Report Notes, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - PA -- "Gray Areas" Projects Reviews, 1963 January 10-1964 August 13 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - PA -- Urban Extension Program at Rutgers University, 1963 May-1964 April 20 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - PA -- Transportation and Traffic Safety -- General, 1963 August 6-1965 October 13 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - PA -- Transcript of Notes from Urban Extension Conference (10/27-29/1963), 1963 October-1964 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - PA -- Urban Extension Program at University of California, 1963 November 22-1964 February 16 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - PA -- Urban Extension Program -- General, 1963 December 10-1966 march 28 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - PA -- University of Wisconsin, Columbia County Report Memo, 1964 January 15 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - PA -- John F Kennedy Library and Institute, 1964 January 22-1965 September 7 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - PA -- "The Public Affairs Program, Law Schools and the Administration of Justice" by William Pincus, 1964 February 11 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - PA -- Urban Extension/ACTION Housing -- Memoranda and Report, 1964 February 20-April 15 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - PA -- Urban Extension ACTION-Housing Report, 1964 March 31 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - PA -- "University of Wisconsin Urban Extension Program" by Richard C. Sheldon, 1964 April (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - PA -- Report on University of Oklahoma Urban Science Program, 1964 May (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - PA -- "Review of the Urban Extension Program", 1964 May 11 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - PA -- Kansas City Association of Trusts and Foundations -- Memoranda Re: Grants, 1964 July 20-November 17 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - PA -- MIT and Harvard Joint Center for Urban Studies -- Reports, 1964-1965 March 25 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - PA -- Los Angeles Watts Riots -- General (1 of 2), 1965 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - PA -- Los Angeles Watts Riots -- General (2 of 2), 1966 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - PA -- Oakland Gray Areas Project, 1965 February 2-August 9 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - PA -- New Haven Gray Areas Project, 1965 April 8 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - PA -- Education and World Affairs Proposal Memoranda and Program Report, 1965 April 12-1966 February 21 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - PA -- Los Angeles Watts Riots -- McCone Commission, 1965 August 31-1966 March 1 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - PA -- Report Re: Los Angeles Watts Riots by Malcolm Moos, 1965 September 14 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - PA -- Los Angeles Watts Riots -- News Reports, 1965 October 14-1966 May 22 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - PA - Citizens Crusade Against Poverty -- Memoranda, 1966 January 7-February 1 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - PA -- Los Angeles Watts Riots -- Grant Requests, 1966 March 21-28 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Policy and Planning (PP) -- Teacher Education (1 of 4), 1954-1963 March (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - PP -- Teacher Education (2 of 4), 1965 January 28-October (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - PP -- Teacher Education (3 of 4), 1965 December 1-31 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - PP -- Teacher Education (4 of 4), 1966 February 13-April 7 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - PP -- Behavioral Sciences Program Final Report, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - PP -- Behavioral and Social Sciences -- General, 1957 - 1966 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - PP -- Berlin Program Evaluation Dry Run, 1959 April 14-1964 October 22 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - PP -- Evaluation Reports, 1959 July 17-1965 July (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - PP -- The Brookings Institution -- Institutional Work and FF Grants, 1960 January 28-1965 November 8 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - PP -- "Report on Urban Studies Program at the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill", 1960 April 27 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - PP -- Henry T. Heald/Wilson McNeil Lowry Memoranda, 1961 January 14-1965 May 4 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - PP -- Behavioral and Social Sciences -- Reports and Supporting Materials, 1962-1963 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - PP -- Behavioral and Social Sciences -- University of Rochester -- FF Grants, 1962-1966 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - PP -- Grant Records, 1962-1966 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - PP -- "An Evaluation of The Ford Foundation Grants to California, Chicago, Columbia, Harvard, Princeton and Yale Universities to Establish Rotating Research Professorships in American Governmental Affairs" by Marion Clawson, 1962 February (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - PP -- Program Planning Budget, 1962 June 11-1964 June 8 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - PP -- Staff Miscellaneous, 1962 June 20-1965 November 1 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - PP -- Appropriation for Planning and Evaluation Studies, 1962 October 12-1963 December 23 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - PP -- Civil Rights and Inter-Group Relations Proposals and Ideas, 1962 November 6-1965 August 23 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - PP -- Approved Administrative Budgets, 1963-1966 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - PP -- Travel and Study Awards -- General Correspondence and Memoranda (1 of 2), 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - PP -- Travel and Study Awards -- General Correspondence and Memoranda (2 of 2), 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - PP -- The Greater Cleveland Associated Foundation -- Appointment Schedules and Background Materials, 1963-1965 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - PP -- Miscellaneous -- Memoranda Re: Travel, etc., 1963 February 15-1966 September 13 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - PP -- Evaluation of Gray Areas -- General, 1963 May 7-1964 July 6 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - PP - Articles on the Ford Foundation, 1963 May 15 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - PP -- Evaluation of Gray Areas Project -- New Haven, 1963 July 14-1965 April 8 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - PP -- Year End Program Planning Budget Modifications and Memoranda, 1963 July 24-September 23 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - PP -- "New Ideas for Cities as Learned from Foundation Grants" by Paul N. Ylvisaker, 1963 August 12 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - PP -- Negro Education -- General, 1963 September 11-1966 August 3 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - PP -- Center for Advanced Studies in the Behavioral Sciences, 1963 October 1-1965 February 17 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - PP -- "Historic and Architectural Preservation and Restoration" -- Discussion Paper and Memorandum, 1963 December-1966 June 7 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - PP -- "The Educational and Other Development of the Negro" Discussion Paper, 1963 December 6-1965 August 20 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - PP -- University of Wisconsin Evaluation -- General, 1963 December 6-1966 July 27 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - PP -- Basic Policy Planning, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - PP -- Evaluations of Foundation Programs, 1964-1965 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - PP -- Stanford University Evaluation, Reports, Articles, Miscellaneous, 1964-1966 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - PP -- Institute of International Education (IIE) Evaluation Correspondence, 1964 February 12-1966 February 8 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - PP -- Discussion Papers and Evaluations, Board Meetings/Progress Reports, 1964 April 24-1965 June 22 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - PP -- Evaluation of Gray Areas Projects -- Oakland, 1964 July 1-1965 July 27 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - PP -- President's Staff Meeting -- Memoranda, 1964 July 6-1965 July 12 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - PP -- "Support of Regranting Activities" -- Report, Correspondence and Memoranda, 1964 August 19-September 21 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - PP -- Endowment Grants Memoranda, 1964 September 11-1966 September 16 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - PP -- PP Analyses (Malcolm Moos, R.C. Sheldon, E.S. Staples), 1964 October 15-22 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - PP -- Academic Exchanges with the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe -- Evaluation Dry Run, 1964 October 16 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - PP -- Foreign Policy Association -- Evaluation Dry Run, 1964 October 16-22 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - PP -- Henry T. Heald Observations on PP Inventories, 1964 December (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - PP -- Teacher Education Evaluation -- Consultants and Miscellaneous Reports and Notes (1 of 2), 1964 December 5-1965 October 8 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - PP -- Teacher Education Evaluation -- Consultants and Miscellaneous Reports and Notes (2 of 2), 1965 November 8-1966 March 1 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - PP -- Agenda for Discussion of Planning Questions, 1964 December 15 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - PP -- Washington Follow-Up on Vice President's Meeting, 1964 December 15-1965 June (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - PP -- Compensation and Benefits Study Committee, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - PP -- Institute of International Education (IIE) Evaluation Supporting Materials (1 of 2), 1965 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - PP -- Institute of International Education (IIE) Evaluation Supporting Materials (2 of 2), 1965 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - PP -- Negro Education Background Material, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - PP -- Stanford University Evaluation, 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - PP -- Teacher Education Evaluation -- General Correspondence (1 of 2), 1965 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - PP -- Teacher Education Evaluation -- General Correspondence (2 of 2), 1966 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - PP -- Washington Correspondence (with Senate, White House, etc.), 1965 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - PP -- Washington Interview Memoranda, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - PP -- Washington Miscellaneous -- Memoranda on Government Meetings, etc., 1965 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - PP -- Washington -- Treasury Report on Tax-Exempt Foundations, 1965-1969 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - PP -- "Some Policy Considerations of Endowment Grants", 1965 January 15 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - PP -- Ford Foundation Programs Developing Federal Activities, 1965 February 15-1966 January 26 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - PP -- Manpower Planning and Development, 1965 February 12-November 3 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - PP -- "The Ford Foundation Programs and Developing Federal Activities" Report Discussed at Officers and Directors Meeting (5/7/1965), 1965 February 23 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - PP -- Vice President's Meeting, Washington (4/7/1965) -- Meeting Materials, 1965 March 11-April 7 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - PP -- Teacher Education Evaluation Interviews (1 of 3), 1965 March 18-November 8 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - PP -- Teacher Education Evaluation Interviews (2 of 3), 1965 November 8-December 20 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - PP -- Teacher Education Evaluation Interviews (3 of 3), 1966 January 25-March 31 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - PP -- Washington Files -- Policy and Planning Questions, 1965 March 30 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - PP -- Policy and Planning Questions -- Meetings with Domestic Programs, 1965 March 30-June 11 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - PP -- Policy and Planning Questions -- Meetings with International Programs, 1965 March 30-June 10 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - PP -- Negro Education Conversation Memoranda, 1965 April 9-1966 July 26 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - PP -- Information Coordinating Unit -- Memoranda Re: Possible Establishment of Unit, 1965 April 23-May 14 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - PP -- Policy and Planning Assignments, 1965 May 17-November 14 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - PP -- Institute of International Education (IIE) Evaluation Interview Memoranda, 1965 August 4-1966 March 18 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - PP -- The Greater Cleveland Foundation Evaluation Correspondence, 1965 October 6-1966 February 4 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - PP -- Education Budget Memoranda, 1965 April 29-1966 February 15 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - PP -- Teacher Education Evaluation Meetings, 1965 June 9-1966 January 21 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - PP -- The Ford Foundation/Jackson State College Conference, 1965 July 6-August 10 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - PP -- Educational and Other Development of the Negro Memorandum, 1965 August 4 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - PP -- Automotive Safety Study, 1965 August 6-1966 March 1 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - PP -- "The Ford Foundation Programs and Developing Federal Activities", 1965 September (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - PP -- "The Ford Foundation Training Associate Program", 1965 October (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - PP -- Ford Foundation Statement for Proposed New York State Law on Regulation of Charitable Corporations, 1965 December 27-1966 January 21 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - PP -- Proposed State Registration of Foundations, 1965 December 27-1966 January 21 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - PP -- Drug Addiction -- Correspondence, Memoranda, Report, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - PP -- Ford Foundation's Future Income and Asset Projections, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - PP -- Graduate Education -- Correspondence (1 of 2), 1966 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - PP -- Graduate Education -- Correspondence (2 of 2), 1966 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - PP -- Graduate Education -- General -- Staff Memoranda, Statistics, Reports (1 of 2), 1966 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - PP -- Graduate Education -- General -- Staff Memoranda, Statistics, Reports (2 of 2), 1966 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - PP -- Graduate Education University Memoranda (1 of 2), 1966 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - PP -- Graduate Education University Memoranda (2 of 2), 1966 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - PP -- The Greater Cleveland Associated Foundation Evaluation Report, 1966 January (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - PP -- Report of Foundation Salary and Benefits Policies, 1966 January (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - PP -- American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) Sessions at Berkeley, 1966 January 5-6 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - PP -- Science and Engineering Budget Memoranda, 1966 January 25 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - PP -- Special Programs Budget Memoranda, 1966 January 28-February 16 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - PP -- Teacher Education Evaluation Notes, 1966 January 28-March 1 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - PP -- Ford Foundation and the Press, 1966 February 9-21 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - PP -- Population Budget Memoranda, 1966 February 9-23 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - PP -- Program Planning Budget Memoranda, 1966 February 10-March 24 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - PP -- International Affairs Budget Memoranda, 1966 February 24-March 16 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - PP -- Minority Group Problems Committee -- General -- Memoranda, 1966 May 18-September 27 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - PP -- Possible PhD Program General Memoranda, 1966 May 20-November 29 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - PP -- Columbia University General Campaign, 1966 May 23-June 28 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - PP -- "The Negro and the Ford Foundation" by Calvin Kytle (Consultant) and General Correspondence, 1966 May 23-August 8 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - PP -- Henry Ford Memorial Museum Evaluation, 1966 May 27 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - PP -- National Commission on Drug Dependency -- General -- Memoranda, 1966 June 15-23 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - PP -- Graduate Education Interview Notes, 1966 June 17-July 11 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - PP -- Graduate Education Memoranda, 1966 June 21-29 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - PP -- Graduate Education Miscellaneous Memoranda, 1966 June 23-August 5 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - PP -- Graduate Education Study -- General -- Memoranda and Correspondence, 1966 July 3-August 24 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - PP -- Possible PhD Program Guidelines, 1966 July 10-August 5 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - PP -- New Titles and Assignments for Ford Foundation Professional Staff, 1966 December 22 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Population (POP) -- General -- Memoranda Re: Population Program, 1952 December 15-1966 May 25 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - POP -- Population Council Data, 1962 January 25-1964 September 24 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - POP -- International Planned Parenthood Federation -- Memoranda, Proposals Re: Foundation Grants, 1962 June 8-1966 March 1 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - POP -- Miscellaneous Reports Re: Population Problems, Foundation Work, Family Planning Programs, Birth Control, etc., 1962 December 11-1964 October 30 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - POP -- Policy/Position Papers, 1963 January 23-March 29 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Science and Engineering (SE) -- General -- Memoranda, Background on Science and Engineering Program, 1960 November 9-1966 April 5 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - SE -- Conservation -- Memoranda and Report Re: Resources and the Environment, 1962 August 29-1966 January 15 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - SE -- Resources for the Future Reports, 1963 February (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - SE -- Resources for the Future Correspondence, 1963 March 8-1965 June 3 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Special Projects (SPE) -- Special Program in Education -- Memoranda Re: Foundation Grants, 1959 September 8-1964 November 6 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - SPE -- General -- Memoranda Re: Foundation Grants, 1963 May 3-1966 May 17 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Speeches and Writings, 1955-1974; V
  These files consist of transcripts, speeches, speaking notes, and published and unpublished articles by Mr. Lowry on the subjects of education and the arts. Of note is Mr. Lowry's testimony on three occasions before the House Select Subcommittee on Education. There is also a single speech by Paul Ylvisaker, another Ford Foundation employee, on urbanization.
  Files are arranged by person and then chronologically by date of speech, interview or publication.
  Sound recordings
  - General -- Index, Press Release, 1964-1970 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Studio Arena Theatre Conference, Wilson McNeil Lowry speech, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Studio Arena Theatre Conference, Wilson McNeil Lowry speech - Reel I, 1967; 1/4 inch audio tape; Sound, 50 minutes (Box 28, Reel AV 6311)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Access copy available.
      Part one of conference speech given by Wilson McNeil Lowry.
    - Studio Arena Theatre Conference, Wilson McNeil Lowry speech - Reel II, 1967; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 28, Reel AV 6312)
      Access Restrictions
      Part two of conference speech given by Wilson McNeil Lowry.